Have the adventure of your life keeping up with the Joneses.
Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade is a adventure,
action film directed by Steven Spielberg.
In 1938, an art collector appeals to eminent archaeologist Dr.
Indiana Jones to embark on a search for the Holy Grail.
Indy learns that a medieval historian has vanished while searching
for it, and the missing man is his own father, Dr.
Henry Jones Sr..
He sets out to rescue his father by following clues in the old man's
notebook, which his father had mailed to him before he went missing.
Indy arrives in Venice, where he enlists the help of a beautiful academic, Dr.
Elsa Schneider, along with Marcus Brody and Sallah.
Together they must stop the Nazis from recovering the power
of eternal life and taking over the world!
Indiana Jones, played by Harrison Ford.
Professor Henry Jones, played by Sean Connery.
Marcus Brody, played by Denholm Elliott.
Elsa, played by Alison Doody.
Sallah, played by John Rhys-Davies.
Walter Donovan, played by Julian Glover.
Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade is a 1989 American action-adventure film directed by Steven Spielberg
from a screenplay by Jeffrey Boam, based on a story by George Lucas and Menno Meyjes.
It is the third installment in the Indiana Jones film series and the
narrative sequel to Raiders of the Lost Ark (1981).
Harrison Ford reprises his role as the titular character,
while Sean Connery co-stars as his father.
Other cast members featured include Alison Doody, Denholm Elliott,
Julian Glover, River Phoenix and John Rhys-Davies.
In the film, set in 1938, Indiana Jones searches for his father, a Holy Grail scholar, who has been
kidnapped and held hostage by the Nazis while on a journey to find the Holy Grail.
After the criticism that Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom (1984) received, Spielberg chose to make a more
lighthearted film for the next installment, as well as bringing back several elements from Raiders of the Lost Ark.
During the five years between Temple of Doom and The Last Crusade, he and executive
producer Lucas reviewed several scripts before accepting Jeffrey Boam's.
Filming locations included Spain, Italy, West Germany,
Jordan, the United Kingdom, and the United States.
Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade was released in the United
States on May 24, 1989, by Paramount Pictures.
The film received positive reviews and was a financial success, earning $474.2
million worldwide, making it the highest-grossing film of 1989.
It also won the Academy Award for Best Sound Effects Editing and was nominated
for Best Original Score and Best Sound at the 62nd Academy Awards.
Although Spielberg and Lucas originally intended for The Last Crusade to be the end of the series, a sequel, Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the
Crystal Skull, followed in May 2008, while a fifth and final film, Indiana Jones and the Dial of Destiny, was released in June 2023.
The film explores themes of saving the world, nazi,
holy grail, venice, italy, entrapment.